<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 15:09:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/security/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Impact of OpenVPN Port Sharing</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/performance-impact-of-openvpn-port-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 15:09:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/performance-impact-of-openvpn-port-sharing/</guid>
      <description>I recently had cause to use OpenVPN on the standard HTTPS port to protect my traffic. This was done as a compromise with administrators who didn&#39;t want to change their egress filtering, but wanted to allow me to continue doing my normal work.
I already run several webservers, including this one, and didn&#39;t want to give up exclusive access to the precious TCP port 443. The recommended way to deal with this is to make use of the port-share option built into OpenVPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Your Own DNS-over-TLS Server</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/run-your-own-dns-over-tls-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 15:09:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/run-your-own-dns-over-tls-server/</guid>
      <description>DNS-over-TLS is a relatively new privacy enhancing protocol that encrypts all of your DNS requests to a trusted server. In an age when airports, and coffee shops are outsourcing &amp;lsquo;free wifi&amp;rsquo; to corporate entities that are likely harvesting as much data as they can this is a nice addition. I largely use VPNs when connected to these access points which provides at least as good protection as DNS-over-TLS which has caused me to largely overlook this development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Never the Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/10/its-never-the-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 13:36:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/10/its-never-the-firewall/</guid>
      <description>This last Thursday I had the privilege of giving a talk at our local Linux User Group about diagnosing firewall issues on Linux entitled &amp;ldquo;It&#39;s Never the Firewall: Diagnosing Linux Firewall Issues&amp;rdquo;. I really enjoyed giving the talk, however, I left a few questions unanswered. While I may do a more extensive post on everything that I went through in the talk (I have been lax on writing content for this blog), this post is more to answer the outstanding questions and of course to make my slides available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syslog-NG</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 01:56:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</guid>
      <description>Syslog-NG is a fast, reliable, and secure syslog daemon that can do advanced processing and log centralization while maintaining a sane configuration file syntax. I&#39;ve recently come to vastly prefer it over my previous long term favorite Rsyslog.
It&#39;s important to note that when modifying the logs statements, they will be processed in order. This means log statements that finalize a message will never make it past that statement. This finalization behavior can be a great tool for optimizing the processing path of logs but can result in unexpected behavior if you don&#39;t pay attention when re-ordering the statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFSSL</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/cfssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 18:39:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/cfssl/</guid>
      <description>CFSSL is a toolkit of utilities for TLS PKI infrastructures and supports more functionality than I&#39;ve personally needed. It is a fast and convenient way to setup and manage a multi-layer internal certificate authority.
I&#39;ve used it to generate an internal root CA, with sub-CAs for internal only server certificates, and separate CAs for each domain of client certificates (such as VPN, log, mail, and LDAP servers). This allows the root CA to be protected more stringently than specific domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&#39;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&#39;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPTables</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/iptables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:14:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/iptables/</guid>
      <description>iptables (and ip6tables) is a simple application for interacting directly with the Linux kernel&#39;s netfilter firewall. nftables is attempting to replace it. nftables has better performance but is incredibly complex and difficult to use. Until the tooling and usability around nftables is addressed iptables will likely remain the reigning champion.
It is important that your systems have effective ingress and egress rules. Depending on your host OS, you&#39;ll find your rule set stored in different locations but the following list are where I&#39;ve seen them before:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Principles</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 05:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing current security hardening practices put out by several organizations and attempting to filter the good recommendations from the outdated legislated requirements, I came across one of the best descriptions of basic security principles. You can find it in the NIST Guide to General Server Security (published in 2008).
I&#39;ve replicated section 2.4 from the linked document (I have removed the footnotes, but it is otherwise unchanged) in its entirety here for safe keeping and to hopefully help expose this to more people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable Smart Cards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the WiFi vulnerability a much more limited vulnerability was announced around private GPG keys that were generated using Infineon&#39;s RSA Library version v1.02.013.
The vulnerability lies in shortcuts taken to speed up the key generation using the library. The performance increase makes the private key vulnerable to factorization attacks using an extension to Coppersmith&#39;s attack.
It has been confirmed that YubiKey 4s are effected as are many nations national ID cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A KRACK In the Defenses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</guid>
      <description>An advisory from US CERT has been circulating for the last week about a protocol level flaw in WPA &amp;amp; WPA2. The advisory itself was:
 US-CERT has become aware of several key management vulnerabilities in the 4-way handshake of the Wi-Fi Protected Access II (WPA2) security protocol. The impact of exploiting these vulnerabilities includes decryption, packet replay, TCP connection hijacking, HTTP content injection, and others. Note that as protocol-level issues, most or all correct implementations of the standard will be affected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>