<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/security/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Vulnerable Smartcards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smartcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smartcards/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the WiFi vulnerability a much more limited vulnerability was announced around private GPG keys that were generated using Infineon&amp;rsquo;s RSA Library version v1.02.013.
The vulnerability lies in shortcuts taken to speed up the key generation using the library. The performance increase makes the private key vulnerable to factorization attacks using an extension to Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack.
It has been confirmed that Yubikey 4s are effected as are many nations national ID cards.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>A KRACK In the Defenses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</guid>
      <description>An advisory from US CERT has been circulating for the last week about a protocol level flaw in WPA &amp;amp; WPA2. The advisory itself was:
 US-CERT has become aware of several key management vulnerabilities in the 4-way handshake of the Wi-Fi Protected Access II (WPA2) security protocol. The impact of exploiting these vulnerabilities includes decryption, packet replay, TCP connection hijacking, HTTP content injection, and others. Note that as protocol-level issues, most or all correct implementations of the standard will be affected.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Auditd</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/auditd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 15:33:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/auditd/</guid>
      <description>Auditd collects any configured syscall execution with critical security metadata associated with the event. This can help enrich other security tools such as AIDE to determine what user and process are responsible for the change.
For reliable operation the rules should be carefully tuned to your system. Tracking every write to disk will generate an unreasonable amount of events and depending on the configuration of the kernel&amp;rsquo;s audit subsystem, may trigger a kernel panic.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>AIDE</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/aide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 02:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/aide/</guid>
      <description>AIDE (Advanced Intrusion Detection Environment) is a file and directory integrity checker that compares the current hashes, permissions, and attributes of files directories against a known database built from the system.
This can be run periodically to detect manipulation of critical system files, though a motivated attacker with an appropriate level of permissions could modify this database or disable the check as long as the system is able to write to it.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Yubikey</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/yubikey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/yubikey/</guid>
      <description>Smart Card NEO dnf install ykpers -y ykpersonalize -m82  Unplug and replug it back in and it should be usable as a smartcard.
NFC / HTTP Auth dnf install ykpers -y ykpersonalize -n https://api.stelfox.net/sessions/yknfc?t=  This will hit the API with a URL like: https://api.stelfox.net/session/yknfc?t=ccccccuddclhrkuvurcufviveulljleihvreukifegjh
The API can then return a token that for accessing additional functionality.
Resetting This will wipe all keys, user, and admin pins on the card.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>GPG Process Notes</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/gpg-process-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 23:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/gpg-process-notes/</guid>
      <description>I followed the TAILS setup guide to get a secure offline environment running to perform this generation task. The steps I took are documented in the tails document.
Initial Key Creation For simplicity I wanted to clear out the GnuPG configuration that starts out in place. Makes things a lot nicer later on.
rm -rf ~/.gnupg/*  I pulled in the .gnupg/gpg.conf from my dotfiles by hand.
And begin the key generation process</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Better Practices With Sudo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/better-practices-with-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:45:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/better-practices-with-sudo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work with a lot of different linux machines from embedded devices, to cloud
servers and open stack hosts. For many of them I&amp;rsquo;m either the sole
administrator or one of three or less with administrative access. Where there
are multiple administrative users, we all are generally working as backups to
each other. We use sudo whenever we need to execute a task with privileges on
any of these machines with no direct root login permitted remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must confess I have established two habits over time that are against best
practices with regard to sudo; Using it to execute a root shell only, and not
restricting which commands can be run with sudo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>SPF &amp; DKIM Records in Route 53</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/spf-and-dkim-records-in-route-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 10:46:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/spf-and-dkim-records-in-route-53/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a more detailed post on emailing from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure soon, but in the meantime I wanted to quickly throw out solutions too a couple of problems I encountered. These are all specific too Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Route 53, and most are user error (myself).
SPF Invalid Characters or Format After generating my SPF record, I jumped into Route 53, created a new record pasted in my record, attempted to save and received the following message:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unregistering From WhisperPush After Flashing a New ROM</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/unregistering-from-whisperpush-after-flashing-a-new-rom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 21:54:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/unregistering-from-whisperpush-after-flashing-a-new-rom/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with my Nexus 5 lately. It was quickly rooted and I began playing with various ROMs that had been pre-built for the Nexus 5. My first stop was the CyanogenMod. Since I&amp;rsquo;d last used CyanogenMod they added a built-in framework that provides transparent text message encryption called WhisperPush.
WhisperPush is an implementation of Moxie Marlinspike&amp;rsquo;s highly respected TextSecure and I was very excited at the possibility of using it.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Calculating RSA Key Fingerprints in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/04/calculating-rsa-key-fingerprints-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 18:37:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/04/calculating-rsa-key-fingerprints-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>I regularily find myself working on projects that involve the manipulation and storage of RSA keys. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve never had to worry about identification or presentation of these keys. Normally I&amp;rsquo;ve only got one too three pairs at most that I&amp;rsquo;m manipulating (server, certificate authority, client).
I&amp;rsquo;ve not found myself working on a project that involves presenting the certificates to users for selection and comparison. The obvious way too do this is take a page out of other developer&amp;rsquo;s books and present the key&amp;rsquo;s fingerprint.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
