<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/tips/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Fixing Dark Input Boxes in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/04/fixing-dark-input-boxes-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:53:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/04/fixing-dark-input-boxes-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I recently began trying out Cinnamon as my desktop environment and I&#39;ve been thoroughly enjoying it. The only issue I was having was occasionally a page&#39;s form input fields would have a dark background while still having dark text making it impossible to read, and very difficult to write.
It wasn&#39;t happening everywhere, and I couldn&#39;t track down what about a website would cause the issue. Most prominently for me was when this showed up in AWS&#39;s interface.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Reflashing Cisco Catalyst With XMODEM</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/reflashing-cisco-catalyst-with-xmodem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:26:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/reflashing-cisco-catalyst-with-xmodem/</guid>
      <description>One of the Cisco Catalyst 3750 I had to work on recently had it&#39;s flash completely wiped. When this happens you can only flash the filesystem using the XMODEM serial console. This is a fairly well documented process on Windows. On Linux most of the documented ways involve switching between multiple utilities and can be tricky. I wanted to documented how I did this and possibly help other in the same situation.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Hosting Your Own Private Git Repo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/12/hosting-your-own-private-git-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 18:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/12/hosting-your-own-private-git-repo/</guid>
      <description>Git was built and developed with the intention of being a distributed reversion control system. Most people now use it with one or another central repository even when working on large teams which is perfectly fine if that model works for you and your team.
It can be useful to quickly work with others on private repositories without requiring them to get on your platform of choice, or for sensitive repositories keep the repository entirely under your control.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>SPF and Google Site Verification in Route 53</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 11:36:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</guid>
      <description>Route53 doesn&#39;t allow multiple definitions of the same name/type pair of DNS entries which is quite a headache. This is the first time I&#39;ve had a conflict of a TXT record in Route53 at the base, specifically both Google&#39;s site verification, and SPF records both want to live at the root of the domain. The site verification record needs to stay around as Google periodically re-verifies the domain.
To get this to work you need to quote both the Google verification string and the SPF record, but you also have to ensure that there is a newline in the field.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Timelapse of a Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/timelapse-of-a-linux-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:37:39 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/timelapse-of-a-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <description>I have the privilege of working full remote. To stay connected with our other remote workers and the main office we keep a live video conference going all the time. It&#39;s pretty convenient and definitely allows me to continue to feel connected with the company.
During one of our stand ups, a coworker mentioned that they&#39;d like to see how things looked over time. I have three 1440p monitors and largely leave the video conference on my right most window, which makes recording (an audio free) timelapse pretty easy with FFmpeg.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Parsing HTTP Responses in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/parsing-http-responses-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 07:53:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/parsing-http-responses-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Normally handling HTTP responses in Ruby is rather straight forward. There is a native library in Ruby that handles HTTP requests which parses the responses into a neat data structure that you can then operate on. What if you want to work on stored HTTP responses outside of a connection though? This was the situation I found myself in and thanks to a series of unusual decisions in the Ruby core library I found myself left out in the cold.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting OpenLDAP Schemas to LDIF</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been writing software to work against an OpenLDAP instance, with a highly customized schema. The operators of the existing system only had the schema files and searching around found several elaborate ways to convert the files which I tried with mixed success. After doing the research to figure this out, it became clear I could probably have used slapcat and have dumped the active schema directly to LDIF.
As a sample of how I converted these, I&#39;ll use the rfc2307bis.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Including LDIF Files in OpenLDAP</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</guid>
      <description>While setting up and OpenLDAP server I found my distribution shipped with a couple of schema files, but no equivalent LDIF files. I found ways to convert the file using slapcat and slaptest and the files were valid on their own.
I was specifically trying to bootstrap an OpenLDAP server, with it&#39;s schema, from scratch for a CI/CD system to test against. To accomplish this I was making use of the include directive in a configuration LDIF file and saw some very odd behavior.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Cross-Compiling Gentoo for Xilinx Boards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 17:49:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you&#39;ve come here looking to build a root filesystem for 32 bit ARM devices I suspect everything but the build tuple will be the same. The issues that need to be worked around largely packaging and profile issues that should all be the same.
I got a hold of a Zynq 7100 development board, and while I&#39;ve played with some embedded ARM microcontrollers such as the STM32F3 series and more basic RISC style microcontrollers like Atmel&#39;s SAMD10 and Atmega lines, I&#39;ve never played with FPGA development before so I considered this an interesting learning opportunity.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting CPIO Files to Tarballs</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 22:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</guid>
      <description>I needed to convert a directory full of CPIO files to tar balls. This quick script did the trick for me but didn&#39;t preserve the user / group. Running it as root will preserve the ownership information but that wasn&#39;t important for my immediate use case.
#!/bin/bash SRC_DIR=$(pwd) for i in *.cpio; do CPIO_TMP_DIR=&amp;quot;$(mktemp -d /tmp/cpioconv.XXXX)&amp;quot; (cd ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cpio -idm &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${SRC_DIR}/${i}&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; tar -cf ${SRC_DIR}/${i%%.cpio}.tar .) rm -rf ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} done </description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unusable Secret Key</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/unusable-secret-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 11:38:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/unusable-secret-key/</guid>
      <description>I use a Yubikey NEO to store subkeys used for signing and authentication. I started experiencing a weird issue with it. It coincided with me rebuilding my system so diagnosing it ended up being harder than normal. The behavior I experienced allowed me to use the key to authenticate (SSH&#39;ing worked fine) but any attempt to sign new data resulted in an &amp;lsquo;Unusuable secret key&amp;rsquo; error. For git this resulted in the following message:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Downgrading Glibc in Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>While refining some automated setup scripts at some point I upgraded to a testing/unstable version of glibc. When I attempted to get the box back on to the stable version I hit a solid protection mechanism built into the portage scripts that prevents downgrading glibc. Attempts will give you the following error message:
 * Sanity check to keep you from breaking your system: * Downgrading glibc is not supported and a sure way to destruction * ERROR: sys-libs/glibc-2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>File in Wrong Format</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently attempting to cross compile a custom Gentoo profile targetting a Xilinx board as I found their distribution to be unmanageable (PetaLinux as hacked together sub-distro of Yocto). I had several issues with the default profile (embedded) conflicting with other critical packages. I&#39;ll do a detailed post later on for building that entire root filesystem.
I came across one issue which didn&#39;t seem to have a well-documented solution.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Gentoo Fstab Failure</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:12:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</guid>
      <description>I use Gentoo with OpenRC quite a bit both for my personal servers and as a compilation test bed for new software since I can control the dependency versions very tightly. I have a set of scripts I&#39;ve been using for quite some time that handle setting up a hardened, fairly minimal install.
I recently encountered a weird issue with them that resulted in an esoteric error that prevented my host from fully booting and leaving the root filesystem read-only.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Investigating LVM From Dracut</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 11:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</guid>
      <description>In my my last post, I covered finding logical volumes that were missing from LVM from within a live CD (which is effectively a whole standard environment). Working with dracut is quite a bit more limited.
Turns out that the commands I&#39;m normally used to for operating and inspecting LVM volumes can all be accessed as a second parameter to the lvm tool like so:
$ lvm vgscan $ lvm pvscan $ lvm lvscan For my particular issue, it led me to notice that block device of my root filesystem was missing due to a missing kernel driver&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Visible Yet Missing Logical Volumes</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/visible-yet-missing-logical-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:58:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/visible-yet-missing-logical-volumes/</guid>
      <description>While working on an automated install script for an embedded board, I hit an issue with the logical volumes never showing up in /dev/mapper, and in turn unable to be mounted. This left me in the dracut emergency shell (after about three minutes), with little to go on beyond the following error:
[187.508531] dracut Warning: Could not boot. [187.510560] dracut Warning: /dev/disk/by-uuid/5681-902D does not exist [187.512534] dracut Warning: /dev/mapper/system-root does not exit [187.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&#39;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&#39;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Linux Audit Rule Paths</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:20:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a little bit of confusion while rewriting my auditd rules which some Googling did not help me solve.
When monitoring a file or directory there are two forms the rules can take. They are effectively equivalent in their functionality. The simpler form is the following format:
-w /etc/shadow -p wa -w /boot -p wa -w /etc/dont_readme -p r These three rules are all behaving slightly differently. The first will audit any writes or attribute changes to the shadow file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Disk Errors</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/disk-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 23:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/disk-errors/</guid>
      <description>This is a weird file&amp;hellip; But while installing gentoo on a disk I started getting a weird error when printing the current partitions on the drive:
Warning: The driver descriptor says the physical block size is 2048 bytes, but Linux says it is 512 bytes. The only thing I&#39;ve been able to find anywhere about this is &amp;ldquo;a low-level device tool (like dd) wrote blocks at the wrong size directly onto the device&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Creating an Empty Git Branch</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 20:47:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I find myself wanting to create a new empty branch in an existing repository. It&#39;s useful for things such as GitHub Pages so you&#39;re able to keep your content source in the master branch while only keeping the output in the gh-pages branch. I&#39;ve also used it for testing a complete rewrite of a code base without the overhead of creating a new repo and copying access permissions.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unbuffered Pipe Filters</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/02/unbuffered-pipe-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 12:49:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/02/unbuffered-pipe-filters/</guid>
      <description>I need to filter a live log stream for only relevant events and quickly hit an issue that I wasn&#39;t expecting. The grep in my pipe chain was waiting until it received all the output from the prior command before it began to attempt to filter it.
Reading through the grep man page I came across the --line-buffered flag which provides exactly what I needed. I wasn&#39;t using the tail command but it serves really well in this situation to demonstrate the use:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Fast Hex to Decimal in Bash</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/08/fast-hex-to-decimal-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 19:50:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/08/fast-hex-to-decimal-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>I needed too turn some hexadecimal values into decimal in a bash script and found a real easy way too do it. The following is a very short bash script demonstrating how too turn the hexadecimal string &amp;ldquo;deadbeefcafe&amp;rdquo; into it&#39;s equivalent decimal value of &amp;ldquo;244837814094590&amp;rdquo;.
#!/bin/bash  INPUT=&amp;#34;deadbeefcafe&amp;#34; OUTPUT=$((0x${INPUT})) echo $OUTPUT </description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Extracting Content From Markdown</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/05/extracting-content-from-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 18:34:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/05/extracting-content-from-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&#39;ve been playing around with building a pure javascript full text search engine for static content sites like this one. One of the challenges with doing this has been working around the Markdown markup embedded in the written content.
Most of the markdown syntax can be stripped out simply by removing all non-alphanumeric characters from the document and move on. This doesn&#39;t solve one of the bigger challenges I&#39;ve experienced&amp;hellip; Code blocks.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>One-Liner SSL Certificate Generation</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/03/one-liner-ssl-certificate-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 14:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/03/one-liner-ssl-certificate-generation/</guid>
      <description>I regularly find myself in need of generating a quick SSL key and certificate pair. I&#39;ve been using a one-liner for a while to generate these certificates. No annoying user prompts just a quick fast certificate pair.
echo -e &amp;#34;XX\n\n \n \n\n$(hostname)\n\n&amp;#34; | openssl req -new -x509 -newkey \  rsa:2048 -keyout service.key -nodes -days 90 -out service.crt &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /dev/null The cert uses the hostname of whatever machine you generated it on.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Finding Ruby Subclasses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/finding-ruby-subclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 07:48:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/finding-ruby-subclasses/</guid>
      <description>While working through a problem I found it would be immensely useful to be able to enumerate all of the current subclasses of a particular class. After thinking about this for a while I settled on a good old friend of mine, ObjectSpace.
For those not familiar with the ObjectSpace module, it is a means to inspect and access the items being tracked by Ruby&#39;s garbage collector. This means it has a hook into every living object, and more dangerously, every near-death object.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Setting Linux System Timezone</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/setting-linux-system-timezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 13:50:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/setting-linux-system-timezone/</guid>
      <description>I change the timezone on the linux systems so rarely that I almost always have to look it up. I&#39;m writing it up here for my own personal reference. With any luck it&#39;ll also help others.
The system timezone is controlled by the /etc/localtime file and is generally symlinked to locale files stored in /usr/share/zoneinfo. Generally I like to keep my systems on UTC as I my machines are in several timezones and it makes all the logs have consistent times.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Updating BMC on Dell PowerEdge C6100</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-bmc-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 21:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-bmc-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</guid>
      <description>I just received my Dell PowerEdge C6100 and found it&#39;s software quite a bit outdated. After searching around quite a bit I found the resources lacking for explaining how to perform these updates. So in this post I&#39;m going to quickly cover updating the BMC firmware on each blade.
The system I received had four different versions of the BMC software installed, additionally Two were branded as MegaRAC and the others branded as Dell.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Updating the BIOS on Dell PowerEdge C6100</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-the-bios-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:39:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-the-bios-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</guid>
      <description>The BIOS was quite a bit more complicated and there was a few options that I had available to try, all of which require either Windows or DOS environments. I don&#39;t have any legal copies of Windows to put on my server and didn&#39;t want to go through all that effort`
It really needs to be done within a DOS environment. I downloaded the file PEC6100BIOS017000.exe from Dell&#39;s support website (locally hosted copy) as well as the 2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Using Dnsmasq as a Standalone TFTP Server</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/using-dnsmasq-as-a-standalone-tftp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 18:29:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/using-dnsmasq-as-a-standalone-tftp-server/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve come across this blog post with the intention of setting up TFTP on an modern version of OpenWRT I have a more recent blog post detailing how too configure your system.
I found myself in need of a TFTP server but wanted to avoid having all of the xinet.d packages and services on my system (even if they were disabled). While looking for alternatives I found out that dnsmasq has a built-in read-only TFTP server.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Running Emails Through Ruby</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/running-emails-through-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 09:32:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/running-emails-through-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Following up on my earlier post where I covered how to backup your Gmail account using fetchmail and procmail; I wanted to cover how I was additionally processing received mail through ruby.
This was part of a larger project where I was doing statistical analysis on my email while evaluating various data stores. To get the emails into the various data stores, I used the ruby script to parse, process and store the emails as they came in.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Downloading Google Mail and Calendar Data</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/downloading-google-mail-and-calendar-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 11:04:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/downloading-google-mail-and-calendar-data/</guid>
      <description>I recently posted a guide on backing up your Gmail with fetchmail. This unfortunately doesn&#39;t include your calendar data. It seems like backing up was a hot enough topic that the Google Gmail team are releasing an official backup method. It&#39;s not completely in the wild yet but I definitely look forward to poking around in it.
Now if only Google let you download everything they know about you as well&amp;hellip; Would definitely make for an interesting read.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Fail Fast in Bash Scripts</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/11/fail-fast-in-bash-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:19:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/11/fail-fast-in-bash-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I found myself writing another bash script that should exit should any of the few commands within it fail to run. As I began writing some error handling after each command, and isolating the sections into bash functions I figured there had to be a better way. After a little Googling and a trip through the bash man pages sure enough:
#!/bin/bash  function error_handler() { echo &amp;#34;Error occurred in script at line: ${1}.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Backing up Gmail with fetchmail</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/11/backing-up-gmail-with-fetchmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 09:55:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/11/backing-up-gmail-with-fetchmail/</guid>
      <description>This morning I found myself in need of a large set of emails to test a particular set of code. Ideally these emails would be broken out into easily digestible pieces, and it was strictly for my own personal testing so I wasn&#39;t concerned with using my own live data for this test (There will probably be another post on this project later on).
Having used fetchmail with good results in the past I decided it was a good idea to take this opportunity to also backup my Gmail account into the common Maildir format (which essentially breaks out emails into individual files meeting my requirements).</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Image Crawler Meets rm -f *</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2009/11/image-crawler-meets-rm-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 21:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2009/11/image-crawler-meets-rm-f/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a simple web crawler that archived any images it found from a site with a large number of backgrounds. I wanted to have rolling backgrounds that almost never repeated.
I let my crawler go and stopped it after a 24 hour period. I ran ls on the directory the images were being saved in to see the results and my ssh session locked up&amp;hellip; Or so I thought. I hit Ctrl-C and nothing happened&amp;hellip; So I closed my window and opened a new one.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Data Recovery</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/data-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/data-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Recovering Data from Swap Sometimes useful bits of information can be recovered from swap. Whether it&#39;s encryption keys, documents that were being worked on or anything else that might&#39;ve ended up in RAM. To search through the swap for interesting bits (and depending on the size this might take a while) you can execute the following command as root or sudo to do it:
[root@localhost ~]# strings `/bin/swapon -s | tail -1 | awk &#39;{print $1}&#39;` | less The command above uses the swapon utility to list all of the swap devices in use; look at the last line of the output (most people only have one swap device); extract only the path to the device node.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
