<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/tips/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&amp;rsquo;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Linux Audit Rule Paths</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:20:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a little bit of confusion while rewriting my auditd rules which some Googling did not help me solve.
When monitoring a file or directory there are two forms the rules can take. They are effectively equivalent in their functionality. The simpler form is the following format:
-w /etc/shadow -p wa -w /boot -p wa -w /etc/dont_readme -p r  These three rules are all behaving slightly differently. The first will audit any writes or attribute changes to the shadow file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Disk Errors</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/disk-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 23:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/disk-errors/</guid>
      <description>This is a weird file&amp;hellip; But while installing gentoo on a disk I started getting a weird error when printing the current partitions on the drive:
Warning: The driver descriptor says the physical block size is 2048 bytes, but Linux says it is 512 bytes.  The only thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find anywhere about this is &amp;ldquo;a low-level device tool (like dd) wrote blocks at the wrong size directly onto the device&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Creating an Empty Git Branch</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 20:47:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I find myself wanting to create a new empty branch in an existing repository. It&amp;rsquo;s useful for things such as Github Pages so you&amp;rsquo;re able to keep your content source in the master branch while only keeping the output in the gh-pages branch. I&amp;rsquo;ve also used it for testing a complete rewrite of a code base without the overhead of creating a new repo and copying access permissions.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unbuffered Pipe Filters</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/02/unbuffered-pipe-filters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 12:49:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/02/unbuffered-pipe-filters/</guid>
      <description>I need to filter a live logstream for only relevant events and quickly hit an issue that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting. The grep in my pipe chain was waiting until it received all the output from the prior command before it began to attempt to filter it.
Reading through the grep man page I came across the --line-buffered flag which provides exactly what I needed. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using the tail command but it serves really well in this situation to demonstrate the use:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Fast Hex to Decimal in Bash</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/08/fast-hex-to-decimal-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 19:50:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/08/fast-hex-to-decimal-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>I needed too turn some hexidecimal values into decimal in a bash script and found a real easy way too do it. The following is a very short bash script demostrating how too turn the hexidecimal string &amp;ldquo;deadbeefcafe&amp;rdquo; into it&amp;rsquo;s equivalent decimal value of &amp;ldquo;244837814094590&amp;rdquo;.
#!/bin/bash  INPUT=&amp;#34;deadbeefcafe&amp;#34; OUTPUT=$((0x${INPUT})) echo $OUTPUT</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Extracting Content From Markdown</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/05/extracting-content-from-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 18:34:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/05/extracting-content-from-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with building a pure javascript full text search engine for static content sites like this one. One of the challenges with doing this has been working around the Markdown markup embedded in the written content.
Most of the markdown syntax can be stripped out simply by removing all non-alphanumeric characters from the document and move on. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve one of the bigger challenges I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced&amp;hellip; code blocks.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>One-Liner SSL Certificate Generation</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/03/one-liner-ssl-certificate-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 14:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/03/one-liner-ssl-certificate-generation/</guid>
      <description>I regularily find myself in need of generating a quick SSL key and certificate pair. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a one-liner for a while to generate these certificates. No annoying user prompts just a quick fast certificate pair.
echo -e &amp;#34;XX\n\n \n \n\n$(hostname)\n\n&amp;#34; | openssl req -new -x509 -newkey \  rsa:2048 -keyout service.key -nodes -days 90 -out service.crt &amp;amp;&amp;gt; /dev/null The cert uses the hostname of whatever machine you generated it on.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Finding Ruby Subclasses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/finding-ruby-subclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 07:48:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/finding-ruby-subclasses/</guid>
      <description>While working through a problem I found it would be immensely useful to be able to enumerate all of the current subclasses of a particular class. After thinking about this for a while I settled on a good old friend of mine, ObjectSpace.
For those not familiar with the ObjectSpace module, it is a means to inspect and access the items being tracked by Ruby&amp;rsquo;s garbage collector. This means it has a hook into every living object, and more dangerously, every near-death object.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Setting Linux System Timezone</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/setting-linux-system-timezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 13:50:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/02/setting-linux-system-timezone/</guid>
      <description>I change the timezone on the linux systems so rarely that I almost always have to look it up. I&amp;rsquo;m writing it up here for my own personal reference. With any luck it&amp;rsquo;ll also help others.
The system timezone is controlled by the /etc/localtime file and is generally symlinked to locale files stored in /usr/share/zoneinfo. Generally I like to keep my systems on UTC as I my machines are in several timezones and it makes all the logs have consistent times.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
