<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>CFSSL</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/cfssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 18:39:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/cfssl/</guid>
      <description>CFSSL is a toolkit of utilities for TLS PKI infrastructures and supports more functionality than I&amp;rsquo;ve personally needed. It is a fast and convenient way to setup and manage a multi-layer internal certificate authority.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used it to generate an internal root CA, with sub-CAs for internal only server certificates, and separate CAs for each domain of client certificates (such as VPN, log, mail, and LDAP servers). This allows the root CA to be protected more stringently than specific domains.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Server Naming Convention</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/server-naming-convention/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 19:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/server-naming-convention/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself using many different naming schemes for servers under my control. I came across a naming convention that finally feels correct. That blog post is quite well written and will let it stand on its own. In the event it ever disappears the important bits (and those where I&amp;rsquo;ve personalized it) are included here.
There are ultimately two or three DNS names that each host receives.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&amp;rsquo;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Mutt</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/mutt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/mutt/</guid>
      <description>I keep a copy of my mutt config both here on the site as well as in my public dotfiles. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll likely document my reasoning, preferences and the tradeoffs made in that config (and change my mind on most in the process).
Vim Since I use vim as my editor I also added the following line to my vim configuration file to autowrap my lines at 72 characters, but only for mutt composed messsages.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>IPTables</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/iptables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:14:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/iptables/</guid>
      <description>iptables (and ip6tables) is a simple application for interacting directly with the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s netfilter firewall. nftables is attempting to replace it. nftables has better performance but is incredibly complex and difficult to use. Until the tooling and usability around nftables is addressed iptables will likely remain the reigning champion.
It is important that your systems have effective ingress and egress rules. Depending on your host OS, you&amp;rsquo;ll find your rule set stored in different locations but the following list are where I&amp;rsquo;ve seen them before:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Syslog-NG</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 19:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</guid>
      <description>Syslog-NG is a fast, reliable, and secure syslog daemon that can do advanced processing and log centralization while maintaining a sane configuration file syntax. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently come to vastly prefer it over my previous long term favorite Rsyslog.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that when modifying the logs statements, they will be processed in order. This means log statements that finalize a message will never make it past that statement. This finalization behavior can be a great tool for optimizing the processing path of logs but can result in unexpected behavior if you don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention when re-ordering the statements.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Security Principles</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 05:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing current security hardening practices put out by several organizations and attempting to filter the good recommendations from the outdated legislated requirements, I came across one of the best descriptions of basic security principles. You can find it in the NIST Guide to General Server Security (published in 2008).
I&amp;rsquo;ve replicated section 2.4 from the linked document (I have removed the footnotes, but it is otherwise unchanged) in its entirety here for safe keeping and to hopefully help expose this to more people.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Linux Audit Rule Paths</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:20:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a little bit of confusion while rewriting my auditd rules which some Googling did not help me solve.
When monitoring a file or directory there are two forms the rules can take. They are effectively equivalent in their functionality. The simpler form is the following format:
-w /etc/shadow -p wa -w /boot -p wa -w /etc/dont_readme -p r  These three rules are all behaving slightly differently. The first will audit any writes or attribute changes to the shadow file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vulnerable Smart Cards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the WiFi vulnerability a much more limited vulnerability was announced around private GPG keys that were generated using Infineon&amp;rsquo;s RSA Library version v1.02.013.
The vulnerability lies in shortcuts taken to speed up the key generation using the library. The performance increase makes the private key vulnerable to factorization attacks using an extension to Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack.
It has been confirmed that YubiKey 4s are effected as are many nations national ID cards.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>A KRACK In the Defenses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</guid>
      <description>An advisory from US CERT has been circulating for the last week about a protocol level flaw in WPA &amp;amp; WPA2. The advisory itself was:
 US-CERT has become aware of several key management vulnerabilities in the 4-way handshake of the Wi-Fi Protected Access II (WPA2) security protocol. The impact of exploiting these vulnerabilities includes decryption, packet replay, TCP connection hijacking, HTTP content injection, and others. Note that as protocol-level issues, most or all correct implementations of the standard will be affected.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
