<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 11:26:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/</guid>
      <description>Here I&#39;ve collected my thoughts over time. If you find anything particularly useful, or in error I hope you&#39;ll take the time to send me an email.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Various Notes</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:35:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/</guid>
      <description>This section contains notes on various services and systems I&#39;ve explored or setup. These are frequently stream of conciousness notes and may have dead ends, multiple attempts, or be outdated. I periodically go through them and attempt to rewrite them to make them more consumable by others and myself.
I hope these can help guide people on their own attempts to understand the services that they host. Please always double check the facts and don&#39;t take a random netizen&#39;s personal assessment will match your use cases.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/about/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for taken an interest in me. Professionally I&#39;m a systems programmer with over a decade of experience of architecting, configuring, maintaining, and operating both local and cloud services. I&#39;ve been a network and systems administrator (Windows &amp;amp; Linux), web developer, security analyst, cloud architect, devops throughout some portion of my career.
Currently I&#39;m working at Minim bringing some of my security knowledge to improving the state of home and IoT security.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Security Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/security/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for taking the time to consider the security of other people! If you&#39;ve found a security vulnerability with any of my infrastructure, I&#39;d greatly appreciate an email. If the vulnerability is sensitive enough, please consider encrypting the contents with my public key.
For additional confidence that key is controlled by me, I encourage you to check the proofs I&#39;ve published on Keybase.
As soon as I receive any reports, I&#39;ll respond as soon as possible then begin confirming it myself.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Site License Information</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/licenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/licenses/</guid>
      <description>Unless otherwise noted all code samples on this site are licensed under the MIT license. Code referenced on other sites or where attribution is directly provided may be under alternative licenses and it is up to the consumer of the content to verify they are compliant with the external licenses.
Post and page prose of this site is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
