<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/linux/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Cross-Compiling Gentoo for Xilinx Boards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 17:49:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you&amp;rsquo;ve come here looking to build a root filesystem for 32 bit ARM devices I suspect everything but the build tuple will be the same. The issues that need to be worked around largely packaging and profile issues that should all be the same
I got a hold of a Zynq 7100 development board, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve played with some embedded ARM microcontrollers such as the STM32F3 series and more basic RISC style microcontrollers like Atmel&amp;rsquo;s SAMD10 and Atmega lines, I&amp;rsquo;ve never played with FPGA development before so I considered this an interesting learning opportunity.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting CPIO Files to Tarballs</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 22:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</guid>
      <description>I needed to convert a directory full of CPIO files to tar balls. This quick script did the trick for me but didn&amp;rsquo;t preserve the user / group. Running it as root will preserve the ownership information but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t important for my immediate use case.
#!/bin/bash SRC_DIR=$(pwd) for i in *.cpio; do CPIO_TMP_DIR=&amp;quot;$(mktemp -d /tmp/cpioconv.XXXX)&amp;quot; (cd ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cpio -idm &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${SRC_DIR}/${i}&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; tar -cf ${SRC_DIR}/${i%%.cpio}.tar .) rm -rf ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} done  </description>
    </item><item>
      <title>XFCE Failed to Connect to Socket</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:23:09 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</guid>
      <description>While trying to build up a minimal Gentoo graphical environment I kept running into an error every time I logged into XFCE from lightdm (I didn&amp;rsquo;t try starting up XFCE any other way). There are tons of blog posts that relate to systemd, ubuntu, or crouton but none related to Gentoo.
The first error message that pops up is:
Unable to contact settings server Failed to connect to socket /tmp/dbus-xxxxxxxxx: Connection refused  Once you click through there was a second error message, but I believe it was due to the previous error and not actually an issue:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unable to Enter LUKS Passphrase</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 21:49:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</guid>
      <description>While setting up a gentoo install with a full disk encryption, I continuously got to a point where the passphrase would show up on boot but I was unable to enter the passphrase. The behavior of the keyboard was also odd, it would toggle it&amp;rsquo;s numlock light every couple of button presses.
Once again this was an issue that was hard to search for, and most other people asking it seemed to only get snarky non-answers which seem so prevalent in forums.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Downgrading Glibc in Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>While refining some automated setup scripts at some point I upgraded to a testing/unstable version of glibc. When I attempted to get the box back on to the stable version I hit a solid protection mechanism built into the portage scripts that prevents downgrading glibc. Attempts will give you the following error message:
 * Sanity check to keep you from breaking your system: * Downgrading glibc is not supported and a sure way to destruction * ERROR: sys-libs/glibc-2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>File in Wrong Format</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently attempting to cross compile a custom Gentoo profile targetting a Xilinx board as I found their distribution to be unmanageable (PetaLinux as hacked together sub-distro of Yocto). I had several issues with the default profile (embedded) conflicting with other critical packages. I&amp;rsquo;ll do a detailed post later on for building that entire root filesystem.
I came across one issue which didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a well-documented solution.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Gentoo Fstab Failure</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:12:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</guid>
      <description>I use Gentoo with OpenRC quite a bit both for my personal servers and as a compilation test bed for new software since I can control the dependency versions very tightly. I have a set of scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for quite some time that handle setting up a hardened, fairly minimal install.
I recently encountered a weird issue with them that resulted in an esoteric error that prevented my host from fully booting and leaving the root filesystem read-only.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Cron Daemon</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/cron-daemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:35:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/cron-daemon/</guid>
      <description>Cron is a pretty standard utility and there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to it. I generally use cronie as my cron daemon with the associated anacron. Cron runs tasks periodically, and anacron helps ensure that a missed task will get run if it was off or powercycled when it would have otherwise run.
File Format The config format differs slightly between crontabs, regular cron files, and anacron entries. At the beginning of all the files environment variables can be set using key=value pairs to control the behavior of cron and anacron followed by entries for that file one to a line.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Syslog-NG</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 01:56:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/syslog-ng/</guid>
      <description>Syslog-NG is a fast, reliable, and secure syslog daemon that can do advanced processing and log centralization while maintaining a sane configuration file syntax. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently come to vastly prefer it over my previous long term favorite Rsyslog.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that when modifying the logs statements, they will be processed in order. This means log statements that finalize a message will never make it past that statement. This finalization behavior can be a great tool for optimizing the processing path of logs but can result in unexpected behavior if you don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention when re-ordering the statements.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Investigating LVM From Dracut</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 11:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</guid>
      <description>In my my last post, I covered finding logical volumes that were missing from LVM from within a live CD (which is effectively a whole standard environment). Working with dracut is quite a bit more limited.
Turns out that the commands I&amp;rsquo;m normally used to for operating and inspecting LVM volumes can all be accessed as a second parameter to the lvm tool like so:
$ lvm vgscan $ lvm pvscan $ lvm lvscan For my particular issue, it led me to notice that block device of my root filesystem was missing due to a missing kernel driver&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
