<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/linux/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Quick and Silent Gigabit Packet Interception</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/quick-and-silent-gigabit-packet-interception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:55:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/quick-and-silent-gigabit-packet-interception/</guid>
      <description>I regularly find myself inspecting traffic on Linux systems. Usually I&amp;rsquo;m already on the client or server when doing this (such as when diagnosing weird low level app behavior, or unknown, or unusual traffic). It has been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve needed to silently be the wire between two black boxes.
While verifying link level information about bypassing my Google Fiber Network Box I needed to be that wire again. Before I connected any wires to anything I needed to be sure I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t accidentally leak traffic as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what would impact the link.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting OpenLDAP Schemas to LDIF</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing software to work against an OpenLDAP instance, with a highly customized schema. The operators of the existing system only had the schema files and searching around found several elaborate ways to convert the files which I tried with mixed success. After doing the research to figure this out, it became clear I could probably have used slapcat and have dumped the active schema directly to LDIF.
As a sample of how I converted these, I&amp;rsquo;ll use the rfc2307bis.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Including LDIF Files in OpenLDAP</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</guid>
      <description>While setting up and OpenLDAP server I found my distribution shipped with a couple of schema files, but no equivalent LDIF files. I found ways to convert the file using slapcat and slaptest and the files were valid on their own.
I was specifically trying to bootstrap an OpenLDAP server, with it&amp;rsquo;s schema, from scratch for a CI/CD system to test against. To accomplish this I was making use of the include directive in a configuration LDIF file and saw some very odd behavior.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Cross-Compiling Gentoo for Xilinx Boards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 17:49:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you&amp;rsquo;ve come here looking to build a root filesystem for 32 bit ARM devices I suspect everything but the build tuple will be the same. The issues that need to be worked around largely packaging and profile issues that should all be the same.
I got a hold of a Zynq 7100 development board, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve played with some embedded ARM microcontrollers such as the STM32F3 series and more basic RISC style microcontrollers like Atmel&amp;rsquo;s SAMD10 and Atmega lines, I&amp;rsquo;ve never played with FPGA development before so I considered this an interesting learning opportunity.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting CPIO Files to Tarballs</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 22:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</guid>
      <description>I needed to convert a directory full of CPIO files to tar balls. This quick script did the trick for me but didn&amp;rsquo;t preserve the user / group. Running it as root will preserve the ownership information but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t important for my immediate use case.
#!/bin/bash SRC_DIR=$(pwd) for i in *.cpio; do CPIO_TMP_DIR=&amp;quot;$(mktemp -d /tmp/cpioconv.XXXX)&amp;quot; (cd ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cpio -idm &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${SRC_DIR}/${i}&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; tar -cf ${SRC_DIR}/${i%%.cpio}.tar .) rm -rf ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} done  </description>
    </item><item>
      <title>XFCE Failed to Connect to Socket</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:23:09 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</guid>
      <description>While trying to build up a minimal Gentoo graphical environment I kept running into an error every time I logged into XFCE from lightdm (I didn&amp;rsquo;t try starting up XFCE any other way). There are tons of blog posts that relate to systemd, ubuntu, or crouton but none related to Gentoo.
The first error message that pops up is:
Unable to contact settings server Failed to connect to socket /tmp/dbus-xxxxxxxxx: Connection refused  Once you click through there was a second error message, but I believe it was due to the previous error and not actually an issue:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unable to Enter LUKS Passphrase</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 21:49:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</guid>
      <description>While setting up a gentoo install with a full disk encryption, I continuously got to a point where the passphrase would show up on boot but I was unable to enter the passphrase. The behavior of the keyboard was also odd, it would toggle it&amp;rsquo;s numlock light every couple of button presses.
Once again this was an issue that was hard to search for, and most other people asking it seemed to only get snarky non-answers which seem so prevalent in forums.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Downgrading Glibc in Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>While refining some automated setup scripts at some point I upgraded to a testing/unstable version of glibc. When I attempted to get the box back on to the stable version I hit a solid protection mechanism built into the portage scripts that prevents downgrading glibc. Attempts will give you the following error message:
 * Sanity check to keep you from breaking your system: * Downgrading glibc is not supported and a sure way to destruction * ERROR: sys-libs/glibc-2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>File in Wrong Format</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently attempting to cross compile a custom Gentoo profile targetting a Xilinx board as I found their distribution to be unmanageable (PetaLinux as hacked together sub-distro of Yocto). I had several issues with the default profile (embedded) conflicting with other critical packages. I&amp;rsquo;ll do a detailed post later on for building that entire root filesystem.
I came across one issue which didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a well-documented solution.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Gentoo Fstab Failure</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:12:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</guid>
      <description>I use Gentoo with OpenRC quite a bit both for my personal servers and as a compilation test bed for new software since I can control the dependency versions very tightly. I have a set of scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for quite some time that handle setting up a hardened, fairly minimal install.
I recently encountered a weird issue with them that resulted in an esoteric error that prevented my host from fully booting and leaving the root filesystem read-only.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
