<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/networking/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>AWS Elastic IP Details</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/aws-elastic-ip-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 16:26:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/aws-elastic-ip-details/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it becomes important to understand how your cloud provider implements certain networking details. While working through an issue in AWS I needed to understand how they handle public IP addressing. While this issue for me was specific to an Elastic IP all of their public addresses are handled this way and may bite you even without them. The problems specifically crop up when a hosted piece of software does NAT traversal detection and changes it&amp;rsquo;s behavior based on the result.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Fighting IPSec on AWS</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/fighting-ipsec-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 21:26:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/fighting-ipsec-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>IPSec is a well known and well understood protocol that is pretty easy to get setup and going&amp;hellip; Most of the time. While setting up an IPSec tunnel to an AWS host I came across a new and unique experience that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have an easily searchable solution.
I had two CentOS 7 EC2 instances, each set up with their own Elastic IP in a default VPC. I installed and configured libreswan with the following config:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>GRE Tunnel</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/notes/gre-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/notes/gre-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>GRE encapsulates all layer 2 traffic, but does so through an unencrypted tunnel. Sensitive traffic should exclusively go through a lower level encrypted tunnel like IPSec.
Firewall The following iptables need to be enabled to allow the GRE traffic to and from the system. This should be restricted to / from IP addresses as well.
-A INPUT -p 47 -j ACCEPT -A OUTPUT -p 47 -j ACCEPT  Manual Setup I&amp;rsquo;ve seen several setups on the internet that make some&amp;hellip; Odd choices.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Thoughts on IPv6 Security and Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2012/07/thoughts-on-ipv6-security-and-mitigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 03:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2012/07/thoughts-on-ipv6-security-and-mitigation/</guid>
      <description>I setup IPv6 on my home network with an OpenWRT router and Hurricane Electric and now I suddenly have an opinion on the state of IPv6 security. This is something that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do for some time and have been mulling over in the back of my mind. I&amp;rsquo;ll go over the details from start to finish of setting up hurricane electric on the router in another post as the information to do so is very scattered and disjointed.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>The Home Network and NAT as a Security Layer</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2011/02/the-home-network-and-nat-as-a-security-layer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 18:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2011/02/the-home-network-and-nat-as-a-security-layer/</guid>
      <description>One of the hot-topics for IPv6 (which I have been thinking about a lot lately) is NAT. I normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about specifics that are obvious to people in my field but for the sake of this post I will. NAT or Network Address Translation, is a way for a large number of computers to share a single public IP address.
The router that is handling the NAT will keep track of connections coming in and out of it and re-write the destination IP to an internal address to keep the traffic flowing.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
