<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on Sam Stelfox</title><link>https://stelfox.net/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on Sam Stelfox</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 22:41:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Podman Socket Compatibility for Metalk8s</title><link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023-05-10-podman-socket-compatibility/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 22:41:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023-05-10-podman-socket-compatibility/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve long appreciated what a project called metalk8s has been doing&amp;hellip; Making Kubernetes run in an opinionated way for private data centers. I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with all their opinions but it&amp;rsquo;s open source and customizable. There is a problem though&amp;hellip;
The docker binary and daemon are largely being replaced and deprecated in favor of podman in the RedHat distros that metalk8s targets. I fully support this change, podman is a great open source tool that listens to user feedback and has far outstripped Docker in capabilities and security features.</description></item><item><title>Modifying the Hosts File in a Docker Container</title><link>https://stelfox.net/blog/modifying-the-hosts-file-in-a-docker-container/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 11:43:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/modifying-the-hosts-file-in-a-docker-container/</guid><description>Before I describe the issue that I encountered, let me be very clear. This hack is potentially dangerous and should absolutely only be done in development environments. This won&amp;rsquo;t affect your host system, only the docker container so the most damage you&amp;rsquo;ll do is prevent hostname and possibly user/group lookups within the container itself.
Alright with that out of the way, I was actively working on a codebase that uses subdomains as part of the identifier.</description></item></channel></rss>