<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Downgrading Glibc in Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>While refining some automated setup scripts at some point I upgraded to a testing/unstable version of glibc. When I attempted to get the box back on to the stable version I hit a solid protection mechanism built into the portage scripts that prevents downgrading glibc. Attempts will give you the following error message:
 * Sanity check to keep you from breaking your system: * Downgrading glibc is not supported and a sure way to destruction * ERROR: sys-libs/glibc-2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>File in Wrong Format</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/file-in-wrong-format/</guid>
      <description>I have been recently attempting to cross compile a custom Gentoo profile targetting a Xilinx board as I found their distribution to be unmanageable (PetaLinux as hacked together sub-distro of Yocto). I had several issues with the default profile (embedded) conflicting with other critical packages. I&amp;rsquo;ll do a detailed post later on for building that entire root filesystem.
I came across one issue which didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a well-documented solution.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Gentoo Fstab Failure</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:12:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</guid>
      <description>I use Gentoo with OpenRC quite a bit both for my personal servers and as a compilation test bed for new software since I can control the dependency versions very tightly. I have a set of scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for quite some time that handle setting up a hardened, fairly minimal install.
I recently encountered a weird issue with them that resulted in an esoteric error that prevented my host from fully booting and leaving the root filesystem read-only.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Investigating LVM From Dracut</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 11:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/investigating-lvm-from-dracut/</guid>
      <description>In my my last post, I covered finding logical volumes that were missing from LVM from within a live CD (which is effectively a whole standard environment). Working with dracut is quite a bit more limited.
Turns out that the commands I&amp;rsquo;m normally used to for operating and inspecting LVM volumes can all be accessed as a second parameter to the lvm tool like so:
$ lvm vgscan $ lvm pvscan $ lvm lvscan For my particular issue, it led me to notice that block device of my root filesystem was missing due to a missing kernel driver&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Visible Yet Missing Logical Volumes</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/visible-yet-missing-logical-volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:58:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/visible-yet-missing-logical-volumes/</guid>
      <description>While working on an automated install script for an embedded board, I hit an issue with the logical volumes never showing up in /dev/mapper, and in turn unable to be mounted. This left me in the dracut emergency shell (after about three minutes), with little to go on beyond the following error:
[187.508531] dracut Warning: Could not boot. [187.510560] dracut Warning: /dev/disk/by-uuid/5681-902D does not exist [187.512534] dracut Warning: /dev/mapper/system-root does not exit [187.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&amp;rsquo;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Security Principles</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 05:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing current security hardening practices put out by several organizations and attempting to filter the good recommendations from the outdated legislated requirements, I came across one of the best descriptions of basic security principles. You can find it in the NIST Guide to General Server Security (published in 2008).
I&amp;rsquo;ve replicated section 2.4 from the linked document (I have removed the footnotes, but it is otherwise unchanged) in its entirety here for safe keeping and to hopefully help expose this to more people.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Linux Audit Rule Paths</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:20:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a little bit of confusion while rewriting my auditd rules which some Googling did not help me solve.
When monitoring a file or directory there are two forms the rules can take. They are effectively equivalent in their functionality. The simpler form is the following format:
-w /etc/shadow -p wa -w /boot -p wa -w /etc/dont_readme -p r  These three rules are all behaving slightly differently. The first will audit any writes or attribute changes to the shadow file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vulnerable Smart Cards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smart-cards/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the WiFi vulnerability a much more limited vulnerability was announced around private GPG keys that were generated using Infineon&amp;rsquo;s RSA Library version v1.02.013.
The vulnerability lies in shortcuts taken to speed up the key generation using the library. The performance increase makes the private key vulnerable to factorization attacks using an extension to Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack.
It has been confirmed that YubiKey 4s are effected as are many nations national ID cards.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>A KRACK In the Defenses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</guid>
      <description>An advisory from US CERT has been circulating for the last week about a protocol level flaw in WPA &amp;amp; WPA2. The advisory itself was:
 US-CERT has become aware of several key management vulnerabilities in the 4-way handshake of the Wi-Fi Protected Access II (WPA2) security protocol. The impact of exploiting these vulnerabilities includes decryption, packet replay, TCP connection hijacking, HTTP content injection, and others. Note that as protocol-level issues, most or all correct implementations of the standard will be affected.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
