<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Sam Stelfox</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Sam Stelfox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 20:33:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accessing NixOS Boot Diagnostic Shell</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/06/accessing-nixos-boot-diagnostic-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 20:33:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/06/accessing-nixos-boot-diagnostic-shell/</guid>
      <description>While working on a complex partition scheme for a NixOS installation, an unexpected hurdle appeared: getting the system to boot. With most Linux distributions, a helpful feature exists where you can gain access to a shell simply by entering the root password if booting goes awry. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the default behavior for NixOS, and discovering how to activate it took a fair bit of digging.
Several NixOS configuration options seemed like they would offer the solution, but to my surprise, they had no effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podman Socket Compatibility for Metalk8s</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/05/podman-socket-compatibility-for-metalk8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 22:41:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/05/podman-socket-compatibility-for-metalk8s/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve long appreciated what a project called metalk8s has been doing&amp;hellip; Making Kubernetes run in an opinionated way for private data centers. I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with all their opinions but it&amp;rsquo;s open source and customizable. There is a problem though&amp;hellip;
The docker binary and daemon are largely being replaced and deprecated in favor of podman in the RedHat distros that metalk8s targets. I fully support this change, podman is a great open source tool that listens to user feedback and has far outstripped Docker in capabilities and security features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining &#34;Subscribers&#34; in Rust&#39;s Tracing Library</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/04/combining-subscribers-in-rusts-tracing-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 20:51:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2023/04/combining-subscribers-in-rusts-tracing-library/</guid>
      <description>Tracing is a fantastic Rust library that I&amp;rsquo;ve found immensely useful, but I feel its documentation and API could still use a bit of polish. At first glance, the distinctions and roles of Subscribers, Layers, Filters, and Writers seem clear and well-documented. But when dealing with less common use cases, understanding their interactions and handling trait-based errors can become challenging.
So, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking I need multiple &amp;ldquo;Subscribers&amp;rdquo; for the various events being traced, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logical Volume in Use</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2020/02/logical-volume-in-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:09:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2020/02/logical-volume-in-use/</guid>
      <description>While attempting to automate some filesytem creation that involved LVM I kept running into an issue occasionally with some holding open the logical volumes. I would attempt to disable the volume using the following command:
$ lvchange -an system/storage Logical volume system/storage contains a filesystem in use. All of the mounts for the filesystems that were on the volume were unmounted, so it must have been a process. The trick to finding this out is to query all the processes mount files to find out what is holding this open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Dracut Built initramfs</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2020/02/extracting-dracut-built-initramfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 18:42:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2020/02/extracting-dracut-built-initramfs/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a hot second since I&amp;rsquo;ve dived into the lands of initramfs and since then it seems like things have gotten more complicated. This is the way of things in tech and usually has a good reason. The simple way that used to work wonders (and is still required) to start with, was to identify if the file is compressed:
$ file /boot/initramfs-current.img /boot/initramfs-current.img: ASCII cpio archive (SVR4 with no CRC) In this case the file appears to be entirely uncompressed which is convenient and likely exactly what you&amp;rsquo;ll experience for reasons I&amp;rsquo;m about to get to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Loop Select in Cinnamon</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/11/blender-loop-select-in-cinnamon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:42:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/11/blender-loop-select-in-cinnamon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been playing around with Blender (following this tutorial series). In Part 4 of the Level 1 series, the host Andrew Price is teaching about loop selects which very simply is holding down Alt while clicking on a vertex. The issue wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for me though I found quite a few other users experiencing the issue.
The most common fix was when people had three button mouse emulation enabled (a common setting people turn on when using laptops or Macs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Hung Nginx Workers</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/10/fixing-hung-nginx-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 11:26:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/10/fixing-hung-nginx-workers/</guid>
      <description>While cleaning up some tech debt, a curious issue cropped up. Nginx was running in an alpine container as a front end load balancer. It had a dynamic config that got periodically updated by a sidecar, and had filebeat shipping logs out to a central collector but otherwise was just a very simple Nginx config.
Every now and then the container would crash, it would automatically recover fast enough no alarms were lost and the clients would just resend their requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Dark Input Boxes in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/04/fixing-dark-input-boxes-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:53:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/04/fixing-dark-input-boxes-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I recently began trying out Cinnamon as my desktop environment and I&amp;rsquo;ve been thoroughly enjoying it. The only issue I was having was occasionally a page&amp;rsquo;s form input fields would have a dark background while still having dark text making it impossible to read, and very difficult to write.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t happening everywhere, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t track down what about a website would cause the issue. Most prominently for me was when this showed up in AWS&amp;rsquo;s interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging Overlapping Subnets</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/merging-overlapping-subnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:11:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/merging-overlapping-subnets/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time there was a single AWS account. In this AWS account was several regions but a single VPC. To make sure expansions into other regions was possible this VPC chose to use the largest private subnet which just so happened to also be the default (10.0.0.0/8).
Another AWS account enter the picture and while they were single they came to the same conclusion and followed the best practices and defaults to their heart&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflashing Cisco Catalyst With XMODEM</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/reflashing-cisco-catalyst-with-xmodem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 23:26:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/reflashing-cisco-catalyst-with-xmodem/</guid>
      <description>One of the Cisco Catalyst 3750 I had to work on recently had it&amp;rsquo;s flash completely wiped. When this happens you can only flash the filesystem using the XMODEM serial console. This is a fairly well documented process on Windows. On Linux most of the documented ways involve switching between multiple utilities and can be tricky. I wanted to documented how I did this and possibly help other in the same situation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
