<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>SPF and Google Site Verification in Route 53</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 11:36:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</guid>
      <description>Route53 doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow multiple definitions of the same name/type pair of DNS entries which is quite a headache. This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve had a conflict of a TXT record in Route53 at the base, specifically both Google&amp;rsquo;s site verification, and SPF records both want to live at the root of the domain. The site verification record needs to stay around as Google periodically re-verifies the domain.
To get this to work you need to quote both the Google verification string and the SPF record, but you also have to ensure that there is a newline in the field.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Timelapse of a Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/timelapse-of-a-linux-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:37:39 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/timelapse-of-a-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <description>I have the privilege of working full remote. To stay connected with our other remote workers and the main office we keep a live video conference going all the time. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty convenient and definitely allows me to continue to feel connected with the company.
During one of our stand ups, a coworker mentioned that they&amp;rsquo;d like to see how things looked over time. I have three 1440p monitors and largely leave the video conference on my right most window, which makes recording (an audio free) timelapse pretty easy with FFmpeg.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Parsing HTTP Responses in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/parsing-http-responses-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 07:53:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/parsing-http-responses-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Normally handling HTTP responses in Ruby is rather straight forward. There is a native library in Ruby that handles HTTP requests which parses the responses into a neat data structure that you can then operate on. What if you want to work on stored HTTP responses outside of a connection though? This was the situation I found myself in and thanks to a series of unusual decisions in the Ruby core library I found myself left out in the cold.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Quick and Silent Gigabit Packet Interception</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/quick-and-silent-gigabit-packet-interception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:55:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/05/quick-and-silent-gigabit-packet-interception/</guid>
      <description>I regularly find myself inspecting traffic on Linux systems. Usually I&amp;rsquo;m already on the client or server when doing this (such as when diagnosing weird low level app behavior, or unknown, or unusual traffic). It has been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve needed to silently be the wire between two black boxes.
While verifying link level information about bypassing my Google Fiber Network Box I needed to be that wire again. Before I connected any wires to anything I needed to be sure I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t accidentally leak traffic as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what would impact the link.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting OpenLDAP Schemas to LDIF</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/converting-openldap-schemas-to-ldif/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing software to work against an OpenLDAP instance, with a highly customized schema. The operators of the existing system only had the schema files and searching around found several elaborate ways to convert the files which I tried with mixed success. After doing the research to figure this out, it became clear I could probably have used slapcat and have dumped the active schema directly to LDIF.
As a sample of how I converted these, I&amp;rsquo;ll use the rfc2307bis.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Including LDIF Files in OpenLDAP</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 20:20:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/03/including-ldif-files-in-openldap/</guid>
      <description>While setting up and OpenLDAP server I found my distribution shipped with a couple of schema files, but no equivalent LDIF files. I found ways to convert the file using slapcat and slaptest and the files were valid on their own.
I was specifically trying to bootstrap an OpenLDAP server, with it&amp;rsquo;s schema, from scratch for a CI/CD system to test against. To accomplish this I was making use of the include directive in a configuration LDIF file and saw some very odd behavior.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Cross-Compiling Gentoo for Xilinx Boards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 17:49:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/cross-compiling-gentoo-for-xilinx-boards/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you&amp;rsquo;ve come here looking to build a root filesystem for 32 bit ARM devices I suspect everything but the build tuple will be the same. The issues that need to be worked around largely packaging and profile issues that should all be the same.
I got a hold of a Zynq 7100 development board, and while I&amp;rsquo;ve played with some embedded ARM microcontrollers such as the STM32F3 series and more basic RISC style microcontrollers like Atmel&amp;rsquo;s SAMD10 and Atmega lines, I&amp;rsquo;ve never played with FPGA development before so I considered this an interesting learning opportunity.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Converting CPIO Files to Tarballs</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 22:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/converting-cpio-files-to-tarballs/</guid>
      <description>I needed to convert a directory full of CPIO files to tar balls. This quick script did the trick for me but didn&amp;rsquo;t preserve the user / group. Running it as root will preserve the ownership information but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t important for my immediate use case.
#!/bin/bash SRC_DIR=$(pwd) for i in *.cpio; do CPIO_TMP_DIR=&amp;quot;$(mktemp -d /tmp/cpioconv.XXXX)&amp;quot; (cd ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cpio -idm &amp;lt; &amp;quot;${SRC_DIR}/${i}&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; tar -cf ${SRC_DIR}/${i%%.cpio}.tar .) rm -rf ${CPIO_TMP_DIR} done  </description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unusable Secret Key</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/unusable-secret-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 11:38:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/12/unusable-secret-key/</guid>
      <description>I use a Yubikey NEO to store subkeys used for signing and authentication. I started experiencing a weird issue with it. It coincided with me rebuilding my system so diagnosing it ended up being harder than normal. The behavior I experienced allowed me to use the key to authenticate (SSH&amp;rsquo;ing worked fine) but any attempt to sign new data resulted in an &amp;lsquo;Unusuable secret key&amp;rsquo; error. For git this resulted in the following message:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>XFCE Failed to Connect to Socket</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:23:09 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</guid>
      <description>While trying to build up a minimal Gentoo graphical environment I kept running into an error every time I logged into XFCE from lightdm (I didn&amp;rsquo;t try starting up XFCE any other way). There are tons of blog posts that relate to systemd, ubuntu, or crouton but none related to Gentoo.
The first error message that pops up is:
Unable to contact settings server Failed to connect to socket /tmp/dbus-xxxxxxxxx: Connection refused  Once you click through there was a second error message, but I believe it was due to the previous error and not actually an issue:</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
