<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Vultr Deny All Firewall</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vultr-deny-all-firewall/</guid>
      <description>While setting up new instances on Vultr for testing, I wanted to initially ensure that no traffic beyond my own could touch the instances. After adding a matching rule for SSH to my IPv4 address, a default rule shows up that drops any unspecified traffic. Switching to the IPv6 I wanted to add a drop all rule (as I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be using IPv6 until the system was up).
The interface only allows accept rules to be created and additionally you&amp;rsquo;ll be greeted with this message while trying to figure out what to do:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Security Principles</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 05:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/security-principles/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing current security hardening practices put out by several organizations and attempting to filter the good recommendations from the outdated legislated requirements, I came across one of the best descriptions of basic security principles. You can find it in the NIST Guide to General Server Security (published in 2008).
I&amp;rsquo;ve replicated section 2.4 from the linked document (I have removed the footnotes, but it is otherwise unchanged) in its entirety here for safe keeping and to hopefully help expose this to more people.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Linux Audit Rule Paths</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 23:20:20 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/linux-audit-rule-paths/</guid>
      <description>I encountered a little bit of confusion while rewriting my auditd rules which some Googling did not help me solve.
When monitoring a file or directory there are two forms the rules can take. They are effectively equivalent in their functionality. The simpler form is the following format:
-w /etc/shadow -p wa -w /boot -p wa -w /etc/dont_readme -p r  These three rules are all behaving slightly differently. The first will audit any writes or attribute changes to the shadow file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Vulnerable Smartcards</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smartcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 12:25:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/vulnerable-smartcards/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the WiFi vulnerability a much more limited vulnerability was announced around private GPG keys that were generated using Infineon&amp;rsquo;s RSA Library version v1.02.013.
The vulnerability lies in shortcuts taken to speed up the key generation using the library. The performance increase makes the private key vulnerable to factorization attacks using an extension to Coppersmith&amp;rsquo;s attack.
It has been confirmed that Yubikey 4s are effected as are many nations national ID cards.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>A KRACK In the Defenses</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 08:23:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/a-krack-in-the-defenses/</guid>
      <description>An advisory from US CERT has been circulating for the last week about a protocol level flaw in WPA &amp;amp; WPA2. The advisory itself was:
 US-CERT has become aware of several key management vulnerabilities in the 4-way handshake of the Wi-Fi Protected Access II (WPA2) security protocol. The impact of exploiting these vulnerabilities includes decryption, packet replay, TCP connection hijacking, HTTP content injection, and others. Note that as protocol-level issues, most or all correct implementations of the standard will be affected.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>The Case of an Empty Executable</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/the-case-of-an-empty-executable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 23:09:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/10/the-case-of-an-empty-executable/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a short article written about a decade ago. It was a curious thing already as it was hosted in a user&amp;rsquo;s home directory off a webserver with the standard &amp;lsquo;~&amp;rsquo; showing up in the URL. The important part that caught my eye was this:
 The &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; program does nothing; it merely exits with a zero exit status. This can be done with an empty file that&amp;rsquo;s marked executable, and that&amp;rsquo;s what it was in the earliest unix system libraries.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Better Practices With Sudo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/better-practices-with-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:45:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/better-practices-with-sudo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work with a lot of different linux machines from embedded devices, to cloud
servers and open stack hosts. For many of them I&amp;rsquo;m either the sole
administrator or one of three or less with administrative access. Where there
are multiple administrative users, we all are generally working as backups to
each other. We use sudo whenever we need to execute a task with privileges on
any of these machines with no direct root login permitted remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must confess I have established two habits over time that are against best
practices with regard to sudo; Using it to execute a root shell only, and not
restricting which commands can be run with sudo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Sharing Context Between Dependent Rake Tasks</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/sharing-context-between-dependent-rake-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 15:46:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2016/02/sharing-context-between-dependent-rake-tasks/</guid>
      <description>I use Rakefiles quite a bit like traditional Makefiles, in that I specify immediate dependencies for an individual task and Rake will execute all of them. If a file or directory is the dependency and it exists, the task that creates it will be skipped. A contrieved Rakefile example might look like:
file &amp;#39;sample&amp;#39; do |t| puts &amp;#39;Creating sample directory&amp;#39; Dir.mkdir(t.name) end file &amp;#39;sample/population.txt&amp;#39; =&amp;gt; [&amp;#39;sample&amp;#39;] do |t| puts &amp;#39;Creating sample population file.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ruby Code Quality Metrics</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/ruby-code-quality-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 16:47:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/ruby-code-quality-metrics/</guid>
      <description>I like getting unopionated feedback on the quality of the code I write. Sometimes I can get this from other developers but they tend to get annoyed being asked after every commit whether they consider it an approvement.
There are a few utilities for Ruby codebases such as flay, flog, and rubocop as well as hosted services such as Code Climate that can help you identify chunks of code that can use some work.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Creating an Empty Git Branch</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 20:47:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2015/04/creating-an-empty-git-branch/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I find myself wanting to create a new empty branch in an existing repository. It&amp;rsquo;s useful for things such as Github Pages so you&amp;rsquo;re able to keep your content source in the master branch while only keeping the output in the gh-pages branch. I&amp;rsquo;ve also used it for testing a complete rewrite of a code base without the overhead of creating a new repo and copying access permissions.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
