<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Servers - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/servers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Servers - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/servers/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Fixing Erratic BMC Controller on PowerEdge C6100</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/06/fixing-erratic-bmc-controller-on-poweredge-c6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 21:43:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/06/fixing-erratic-bmc-controller-on-poweredge-c6100/</guid>
      <description>I randomly started experiencing an issue with one blade in one of my PowerEdge C6100 blades. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t obey all commands issued too it via IPMI or through the BMC&amp;rsquo;s web interface. Additionally the blade would randomly power on when off, and the front light would consistently blink as if a hardware fault was detected.
This has been bothering me for a while, but it was my spare blade and wasn&amp;rsquo;t affecting my lab in anyway so I&amp;rsquo;ve ignored it.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Updating BMC on Dell PowerEdge C6100</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-bmc-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 21:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-bmc-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</guid>
      <description>I just received my Dell PowerEdge C6100 and found it&amp;rsquo;s software quite a bit outdated. After searching around quite a bit I found the resources lacking for explaining how to perform these updates. So in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to quickly cover updating the BMC firmware on each blade.
The system I received had four different versions of the BMC software installed, additionally Two were branded as MegaRAC and the others branded as Dell.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Updating the BIOS on Dell Poweredge C6100</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-the-bios-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:39:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2013/12/updating-the-bios-on-dell-poweredge-c6100/</guid>
      <description>The BIOS was quite a bit more complicated and there was a few options that I had available to try, all of which require either Windows or DOS environments. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any legal copies of Windows to put on my server and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through all that effort`
It really needs to be done within a DOS environment. I downloaded the file PEC6100BIOS017000.exe from Dell&amp;rsquo;s support website (locally hosted copy) as well as the 2.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
