<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nginx on Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/nginx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nginx on Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 11:26:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/nginx/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Hung Nginx Workers</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/10/fixing-hung-nginx-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 11:26:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/10/fixing-hung-nginx-workers/</guid>
      <description>While cleaning up some tech debt, a curious issue cropped up. Nginx was running in an alpine container as a front end load balancer. It had a dynamic config that got periodically updated by a sidecar, and had filebeat shipping logs out to a central collector but otherwise was just a very simple nginx config.
Every now and then the container would crash, it would automatically recover fast enough no alarms were lost and the clients would just resend their requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Your Own DNS-over-TLS Server</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/run-your-own-dns-over-tls-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 15:09:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/11/run-your-own-dns-over-tls-server/</guid>
      <description>DNS-over-TLS is a relatively new privacy enhancing protocol that encrypts all of your DNS requests to a trusted server. In an age when airports, and coffee shops are outsourcing &amp;lsquo;free wifi&amp;rsquo; to corporate entities that are likely harvesting as much data as they can this is a nice addition. I largely use VPNs when connected to these access points which provides at least as good protection as DNS-over-TLS which has caused me to largely overlook this development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weird CloudFlare Behavior</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/10/weird-cloudflare-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 22:36:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>sam@stelfox.net (Sam Stelfox)</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/10/weird-cloudflare-behavior/</guid>
      <description>While working on a replacement webserver, I encountered some odd behavior which took a bit to track down to CloudFlare. This isn&#39;t a bug or an issue with CloudFlare, it was just unexpected.
The server was configured to respond to www.example.tld as well as example.tld, to both encrypted and unencrypted connections. Any requests to the www. domain get redirected to https://example.tld. The config was roughly:
server { listen 80; listen [::]:80; listen 443 ssl http2; listen [::]:443 ssl http2; server_name www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>