<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gentoo - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/gentoo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gentoo - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/gentoo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>XFCE Failed to Connect to Socket</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 17:23:09 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/xfce-failed-to-connect-to-socket/</guid>
      <description>While trying to build up a minimal Gentoo graphical environment I kept running into an error every time I logged into XFCE from lightdm (I didn&amp;rsquo;t try starting up XFCE any other way). There are tons of blog posts that relate to systemd, ubuntu, or crouton but none related to Gentoo.
The first error message that pops up is:
Unable to contact settings server Failed to connect to socket /tmp/dbus-xxxxxxxxx: Connection refused  Once you click through there was a second error message, but I believe it was due to the previous error and not actually an issue:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Unable to Enter LUKS Passphrase</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 21:49:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/unable-to-enter-luks-passphrase/</guid>
      <description>While setting up a gentoo install with a full disk encryption, I continuously got to a point where the passphrase would show up on boot but I was unable to enter the passphrase. The behavior of the keyboard was also odd, it would toggle it&amp;rsquo;s numlock light every couple of button presses.
Once again this was an issue that was hard to search for, and most other people asking it seemed to only get snarky non-answers which seem so prevalent in forums.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Downgrading Glibc in Gentoo</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/downgrading-glibc-in-gentoo/</guid>
      <description>While refining some automated setup scripts at some point I upgraded to a testing/unstable version of glibc. When I attempted to get the box back on to the stable version I hit a solid protection mechanism built into the portage scripts that prevents downgrading glibc. Attempts will give you the following error message:
 * Sanity check to keep you from breaking your system: * Downgrading glibc is not supported and a sure way to destruction * ERROR: sys-libs/glibc-2.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Gentoo Fstab Failure</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 11:12:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2017/11/gentoo-fstab-failure/</guid>
      <description>I use Gentoo with OpenRC quite a bit both for my personal servers and as a compilation test bed for new software since I can control the dependency versions very tightly. I have a set of scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for quite some time that handle setting up a hardened, fairly minimal install.
I recently encountered a weird issue with them that resulted in an esoteric error that prevented my host from fully booting and leaving the root filesystem read-only.</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
