<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</title>
    <link>https://stelfox.net/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws - Sam Stelfox&#39;s Thoughts &amp; Notes</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>Sam Stelfox</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Sam Stelfox</webMaster><atom:link href="https://stelfox.net/tags/aws/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Merging Overlapping Subnets</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/merging-overlapping-subnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:11:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/merging-overlapping-subnets/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time there was a single AWS account. In this AWS account was several regions but a single VPC. To make sure expansions into other regions was possible this VPC chose to use the largest private subnet which just so happened to also be the default (10.0.0.0/8).
Another AWS account enter the picture and while they were single they came to the same conclusion and followed the best practices and defaults to their heart&amp;rsquo;s content.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>AWS Elastic IP Details</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/aws-elastic-ip-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 16:26:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2019/03/aws-elastic-ip-details/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it becomes important to understand how your cloud provider implements certain networking details. While working through an issue in AWS I needed to understand how they handle public IP addressing. While this issue for me was specific to an Elastic IP all of their public addresses are handled this way and may bite you even without them. The problems specifically crop up when a hosted piece of software does NAT traversal detection and changes it&amp;rsquo;s behavior based on the result.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>SPF and Google Site Verification in Route 53</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 11:36:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2018/06/spf-and-google-site-verification-in-route-53/</guid>
      <description>Route53 doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow multiple definitions of the same name/type pair of DNS entries which is quite a headache. This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve had a conflict of a TXT record in Route53 at the base, specifically both Google&amp;rsquo;s site verification, and SPF records both want to live at the root of the domain. The site verification record needs to stay around as Google periodically re-verifies the domain.
To get this to work you need to quote both the Google verification string and the SPF record, but you also have to ensure that there is a newline in the field.</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>SPF &amp; DKIM Records in Route 53</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/spf-and-dkim-records-in-route-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 10:46:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/07/spf-and-dkim-records-in-route-53/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a more detailed post on emailing from Amazon&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure soon, but in the meantime I wanted to quickly throw out solutions too a couple of problems I encountered. These are all specific too Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Route 53, and most are user error (myself).
SPF Invalid Characters or Format After generating my SPF record, I jumped into Route 53, created a new record pasted in my record, attempted to save and received the following message:</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>AWS Reserved Instance Pricing</title>
      <link>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/06/aws-reserved-instance-pricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 13:28:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Sam Stelfox</author>
      <guid>https://stelfox.net/blog/2014/06/aws-reserved-instance-pricing/</guid>
      <description>The current large project I&amp;rsquo;m working on is going to be hosted on AWS and I was requested to do a cost estimate. Looking into it, it quickly became clear that reserved instances could potentially save quite a bit of cash but there was a catch (isn&amp;rsquo;t there always?).
There is an upfront cost for reserving the instance and in exchange you get a reduced hourly rate. After running the numbers one thing wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear too me, is the upfront cost credit towards running machines or a fee you never see again?</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>
